Guide to the Stanford University Objects Collection SC1048
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University objects collection
circa 1840-2017
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University
SC1048
2402 item(s)
Information about Access
Open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Arrangement note
The materials are arranged by accession.
Souvenirs (Keepsakes); Collectibles.; Stanford University
- Objects
  - 100th Big Game - pennant (red and white felt) and mug ("100 years of kickin' axe"), ARCH-AM-1997-021 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    97-021.1 pennant; 97-021.2 mug [slight chip on lip made by PEW on 4/15/2002]
  - 3-ring binder, red leathertte cover with university seal in upper left corner, "STANFORD" in lower right., circa 1977; ARCH-AM-2001-06 (Box 1)
  - 3D photo frames, circa 2016; Accession ARCH-2017-003 (Box 1-2)
    Scope and Contents
    2018-003.1 - Hoover Tower (Box 1); 2018-003.2 - Quad (Box 2), 2018-003.3 - Arches with library and engineering images (on display in Field Reading Room).
  - A Tribute to Leland Stanford. Dedicated to his wife, Jane Lathrop Stanford - poem by James O. Sullivan, July 4, 1893, printed on silk, ARCH-AM-2004-020 (Box 1)
  - Academic gown & hood (PhD) from 1923 commencement, ARCH-AM-1995-07 (Box 1)
  - Academic cap, gown, and MA hood of Harold Bacon (S.U. AB June 1928, MA June 1929), ARCH-AM-1998-011 (Box 1)
    011.1 gown; 011.2 hood; 011.3 cap (in box 2)
  - Academic gowns of Carl Spaeth, ARCH-AM-2007-016 (Box 1)
  - Academic hood (red & white), ARCH-AM-1985-04 (Box 1)
  - Academic Regalia, ARCH-AM-2008-014 (Box 1)
    Box 1 - Robes, Hoods, etc. (RSB); Box 2 - Hat (RSB); Box 3 - Paperweights, Medals, Mugs, etc. (RSB); Box 4 - Miscellaneous items: Swiss Flag, yarmulke, two Mouse pads (Flat); Box 5 - Regalia-Universitat Louvain, Belgium, 1992 (Flat); Box 6 - Regalia-University of Grenoble, 1987 (Flat)
  - Academic Regalia, ARCH-AM-2017-017 (Box 1)
    ARCH-AM-2017-017.01 Cap and Tassle ARCH-AM-2017-017.02 Hood (Blue and Red Velvet) ARCH-AM-2017-017.03 Gown (Trimmed with Blue Velvet)
  - Academic regalia of Pauline Brown (AB, Political Science, '41), 1941-2001; ARCH-AM-2015-011 (Box 1)
    Velvet mortarboard with tassle; gown; hood; pin: "100 S"; pin: "41/Stanford 60th Reunion"; pin: Delta Kappa Gamma (greek letters); lockets (2): gold and red, Leland Stanford Junior Univ. 1891.
  - Academic robe, hood and cap of Donald Henriksen (Ph.D. 1954), ARCH-AM-2009-008 (Box 1)
  - Academic robe of John L. Hennessy, Accession ARCH-2017-008 (Box 1)
    Robe, red with white white embroidered stole affixed.
  - Academic robe, hood, and cap, ARCH-AM-1987-022 (Box 1)
  - Adze found on Frenchman's road (near the "triangle"), ARCH-AM-1998-021 (Box 1)
  - Album cover, Leland Stanford Junior University (leather), ARCH-AM.2014-012 (Box 1)
    Acquisition Information
    Originally part of SC1194 Bacon Family papers
  - Alpenstock used by David Starr Jordan when climbing the matterhorn, ARCH-AM-00-063 (Box 1)
  - Altar cloth, ARCH-AM-1981-03 (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Achievement "golden plate" awarded to Gerhard Casper, May 22, 1997 [gold rimmed plate and brass plague mounted in a frame], ARCH-AM-2000-037 (Box 1)
  - American Flag on Pole, carried to France, WWI, with streamers and metal attached. Pole = 214 long., ARCH-AM-00-263 (Box 1)
  - American flag on pole, with eagle on top. Plaque on pole: "Presented by the American League of California Palo Alto Branch to the Fourth Friends of France Unit Volunteers of Stanford University to the American Ambulance Field Service in France, April 24, 1917", ARCH-AM-00-065.2 (Box 1)
  - Anklet, with partial SU seal (tree with Leland Stanford Junior Univ.), ARCH-AM-1980-10 (Box 1)
  - Anna Lathrop Hewes: bust, in red velvet frame, with curtains, ARCH-AM-00-071 (Box 1)
  - Apports, ARCH-AM-00-073 (Box 1-3)
    Geological Paper Papyrus Seeds Candles bones fabric turtle shell grass skirt
  - Apports, ARCH-AM-00-359
    The collection includes apports that appeared during seances in which Thomas Welton Stanford participated during the years he was involved in, and was a leading figure in, the spiritualist movement in Australia. Among the variety of items included are slates which were supposedly written on by the "spirits" brought to the seances by the medium (of special interest is the slate containing a message from Leland Stanford, Jr. to his uncle, Thomas Welton).
    Also included are various pieces of papyrus, seeds, rocks, a Roman lamp, arrowheads, sharks' teeth, pottery fragments, a tortoise shell, and miscellaneous objects. The dates when the apports were conjured up is unknown.
    - Seeds; Arrowhead; Sharks' teeth; Tile & Pottery Fragments; Rocks (Box 1)
    - Slates (12), with messages written on them (Box 2)
    - Shoulder blade (human bone); Seeds; Tortoise shell; Roman Lamp; miscellaneous objects (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous objects (Box 4)
    - Rocks (taken from a temple in Central America) (Box 5A, Box 5B)
    - Rocks (Box 6A, Box 6B)
    - Rocks; Arrowheads (Box 7)
    - Rocks (Box 8)
    - Rocks (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous objects (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous objects (Box 11)
    - Spiritualists' chart (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous objects; Papyrus; Chinese ink block (Box 13A, Folder 13B, Folder 13C)
    - Papyrus, woven mat, grass clothing, bone weapon (Box 14)
    - Papyrus (Box 15)
    - Papyrus (Box 16A, Box 16B)
    - Papyrus, pencil drawing (Box 17)
    - Papyrus (Box 18A, Box 18B)
  - Architectural medallion by Louis H. Sullivan with detailing by Frank Lloyd Wright., ARCH-AM-1982-15 (Box 1)
  - Archivists Code, Framed. 64X51 cm. 43X31 cm, no glass., ARCH-AM-00-160 (Box 1)
  - Arm band. 40.5x5 cm. Police Stanford Board of Athletic control. No. 305, ARCH-AM-00-200 (Box 1)
  - Art exhibition items from "ReDressing Injustice" part of the conference Feminicide = Sanctioned Murder, 2007; ARCH-AM-2008-028 (Box 1)
    AM 2008-028.1 Dress from art exhibition; AM 2008-028.2 Pink cross used to display the dress
  - Art gallery - original finishes (wood & fabric), ARCH-AM-2002-06 (Box 1)
  - Assorted items found during construction?, ARCH-AM-2008-004 (Box 1)
    2008-004.1 Art Deco style metal frame or belt buckle; 2008-004.2 baggage tag from Daley's Express & Storage co., with ad from Bell's Stables (PA) on reverse; 2008-004.3 one cover from student's note book
  - Assorted items presented to G. Casper during his tenure as president, ARCH-AM-00-017 (Box 1)
    2000-017.1 "For Regina"; 2000-017.2 Framed watercolor portrait of Casper by A. Lyon; 2000-017.3 Stanford Memorial Church limited edition lithograph from original watercolor by Charlotte Severin (56/995); 2000-017.4 plaque from Academic Senate; 2000-017.5 PAC 10 plaque; 2000-017.6 photo of GC in 6th man section at Maples; 2000-017.7 Wooden plaque from DAPER Investment Fund; 2000-017.8 Framed series of 3 photos of GC and someone else on aircraft carrier deck with the words "Well, at least we have one thing in common.. ."; 2000-017.9 Framed cover of U.S. News & World Report ranking of colleges for the year 2000, inscribed and signed by the editor Mort Zuckerman; 2000-017.10 Framed cover of Sports Illustrated for Women, fall 1999, with Logan Tom 2000-017.11 Framed cover of Sports Illustrated with Arthur Lee; 2000-017.12 Framed photo (large) of CG and UC president receiving Koret Foundation checks; 2000-017.13 Framed photo of CG and others from Koret Foundation event; 2000-017.14.Framed photo (small) of CG and UC president receiving Koret Foundation vases; 2000-017.15 Framed photo (small) of CG and others from Koret Foundation event; 2000-017.16. Cartoon from CG's days at Chicago; 2000-017.17. Framed tribute to CG from Sacramento Rotary Club, April 2, 1998; 2000-017.18. Framed print by Libia Kim with caption "From the Windy City to the Farm a Send-Off for Gerhard Casper"; 2000-017.19. Framed gift certificate for Gerhard Casper for $100 for Surgery of Your Choice at UCSF Medical Center; 2000-017.20. Framed letter from Department of Toxic Substances Control, June 20, 1994; 2000-017.21. Framed photo of CG and students "Senior Gift 2000"; 2000-017.22. Framed collage of photographs from "Latkes with Gerhard!" at Serra House; 2000-017.23 Framed acknowledgement from U of Chicago Club of the S. F. Bay Area, 1992; 2000-017.24. Framed photo of Stanford Graduate Fellows presented to President Gerhard Casper April 14, 2000; Fellows' signatures on mat; 2000-017.25. Stanford Associates award to GC as "uncommon athlete", June 8, 2000 [boxed with item 22]; 2000-017.26 List of "words to remember"; 2000-017.27 copy of book on U. S. constitution
  - Assorted library stamps with wooden tray - "Withdrawn" "Claim" "Ref Room Does Not Circulate" "Stanford Libraries" etc., ARCH-AM-2008-023 (Box 1)
  - Assorted printing dies, ARCH-AM-2005-007 (Box 1)
    2005-007.1 S. U. Library seal; 2005-007.2 S. U. Library seal (same as #1); 2005-007.3 Della Taylor sketch of Quad portal with gates in front of it; 2005-007.4 Della Taylor sketch of Quad portal with gates in front of it (same as #3 but reddish tinge and heavier); 2005-007.5 Sketch of a tree (Monterey pine type); 2005-007.6 Hoover Tower [mounted on lead, not wood)
  - Assorted samples from campus buildings, ARCH-AM-2005-030 (Box 1)
    030.1 Wall color from Cooksey House; 030.2 Toyon Hall stucco; 030.3 Flooring from Press warehouse (cross-grain wood block for heavy industrial loads); 030.4 Tower House wooden elements; 030.5 Tower House staircase baluster
  - Assorted SU memorabilia: gold charm (shape of a book with U seal on front, working hinges and 1 page inscribed Senior Ball 1939); image of 1896 baseball team (printed) encased in plastic (Vintage Sports Authority); banjo (Gibson-style Stanford girl painted on skin) and case, ca. 1920; calf-skin painted with ""My Stanford Favorite The Junior Girl"" and an image of a girl, ca. 1910, ARCH-AM-2007-011 (Box 1)
    2007-011.1 charm (in Jewelry box 1); 2007-011.2 1896 baseball team image; 2007-011.3 banjo in case; 2007-011.4 painted calf-skin.
  - Athletic clothing and equipment: football uniform, girls P.E. uniform, football, 2 athletic blankets, plus others, ARCH-AM-1979-12 (Box 1)
  - Athletic medals [not Stanford] awarded to George H. Capron, 1903-1907; ARCH-AM-2010-012 (Box 1)
    2010-012.1 Shattuck School Record 1905 [shot put]; 2010-012.2 Shot Put 1903; 2010-012.3 Minnesota Athletic Conference 1905 220 yds hurtle; 2010-012.4 Minnesota Athletic Conference 1905 discus; 2010-012.5 Minnesota Athletic Conference 1906 discus throw; 2010-012.6 UM Winter Games 1906; 2010-012.7 Northwestern University Interscholastic Discus Throw 1906; 2010-012.8 Northwestern University Interscholastic Shot Put 1906; 2010-012.9 UM Winter Games 1907; 2010-012.10 M.N.G. First Infantry 1905 Discus throw
  - Athletic Medals (11 items - many awarded to C. H. Woolsey ), 1891-1895; ARCH-AM-1990-031 (Box 1)
    90-031.1 Championship [on bar], Pacific Association of Amateur Athletic Union of the United States Running High Jump on hanging emblem; C. H. Woolsey 1892 on reverse 90-031.2 Intercollegiate running broad jump 1894 [on bar], UC and L.S.Jr.U. on emblem [not attached]; Chet Woolsey 22 ft record on reverse 90-031.3 Running hop step & jump [on bar], UC on hanging emblem with date of Nov. 21, 1891; C. H. Woolsey 42 ft. 5 1/2 inches engraved on reverse 90-031.4 California 1894 [on bar], ribbon, and hanging emblem Athletic Games March 1894 90-031.5 Running broad jump 1895 [on bar], D A C on hanging emblem; C. H. Woolsey engraved on reverse 90-031.6 Running hop step & jump [on bar], UC on hanging emblem 90-031.7 Standing broad jump [on bar], UC on hanging emblem 90-031.8 Standing broad jump [on bar], UC on hanging emblem [same as 31.7] 90-031.9 Menlo Circus Club, first place medal 1940 90-031.10 U.C. 95 vs O.H.S. 90-031.11 Ribbon with three decorative pins (no wording)
  - Athletic memorabilia: red felt banners & pennant; figure of football player; letter sweater; beanies; framed banner, circa 1920s; ARCH-AM-1993-13 (Box 1)
  - Athletic ribbons won by Shuer in swimming, 1969-70; 2 field entry ribbons 1974., 1969-1974; ARCH-AM-1995-22 (Box 1)
  - Athletic, Centennial, and other Stanford memorabilia, ARCH-AM-1995-01 (Box 1)
    1. Red flight bag "Stanford Rose Bowl 1972" w/ Indian Head 2. Canvas Bag: SAA, Centennial 3. Button: S. Centennial Celebration homecoming parade and street party 4. Belt Buckle "Stanford" with 3D Indian Head 5. United flight tag "B. Butler Stanford Indians" w/ Indian Head 6. Pocket Pen protector "Stanford University Safety Awareness Prevents Accidents" w/ Lil Injun figure 7. Two name tags for Bob Butler: Centennial and SHS 8. 3 Centennial pins
  - Autograph Book. Jane Stanford's. 20X13X2 cm. Contains autographs of famous people, i.e. Susand B. Anthony and others, 1871; ARCH-AM-00-127 (Box 1)
  - Award ribbons for Holstein-Friesian cattle from Vina Ranch at California State Fair 1911 (11 items and 1 typed note), ARCH-AM-1994-17 (Box 1)
  - Axe handle, purportedly of the original axe, with inscription on metal band: Stanford Axe Handle Presented to Jerry Truatman [sic] Student Body President November 1933 by Fraternity Jewelry Co. (54 inches long), ARCH-AM-2006-027 (Box 1)
  - Axe Committee bag and t-shirt, 2014; ARCH-AM-2015-012 (Box 1)
    Bag, Red and black with white axe and white lettering: "Big Game 2014/Give 'Em the Axe/Stanford Axe Committee."
    T-shirt, black with white/red lettering: "Kiss My [axe logo]"
  - Badge, Football on ribbon. 11x7 cm. Wooden Football suspended from ribbon., ARCH-AM-00-105 (Box 1)
  - Badge, oval felt. "B '12" marron letters on white bkg., ARCH-AM-1984-49 (Box 1)
  - Badges "Director" F.E. Terman R. & E., .8 cm long., ARCH-AM-1984-53 (Box 1)
  - Ball point pen - white with "STANFORD" in red outline text and price of 99 cents, ARCH-AM-2007-025 (Box 1)
  - Balloons with "Tenure Estelle Freedman" and "Support Feminist Studies" - 7 balloons, all a different color, ca. 1982, ARCH-AM-2002-33 (Box 1)
  - Band Hat with Silver Starbust and Red "S" in center, ARCH-AM-2008-018 (Box 1)
  - Bandana from 30th reunion of class of 1971 (red cotton with a variety of symbols in white), 2001; ARCH-AM-2001-32 (Box 1)
  - Bandana from the 2009 Walk the Farm "Biodiversity at Stanford", ARCH-AM-2009-022 (Box 1)
  - Bandana from Walk the Farm 2008: Stanford Waterways, 2008 Apr 26; ARCH-AM-2009-010 (Box 1)
  - Banner (California bear & star) with certificate of authenticity that it was flown on 20th flight of space shuttle - 1985 [possibly wrong banner, certificate says "S.U. flag"], ARCH-AM-1992-20 (Box 1)
  - Banner class of "'60", red felt, white printing. 30x14 cm., ARCH-AM-1984-34 (Box 1)
  - Banner from women's basketball trophy, red with gold trim, brass bar for hanging. 2x21'', c. 1896., ARCH-AM-1984-59 (Box 1)
  - Banner on blue sheet: "Take Back the Night" with crescent moon and fist holding star, ARCH-AM-1994-13 (Box 1)
  - Banner on Pole, 207 cm.; gold fringe blue stars, 103 gold stars., ARCH-AM-00-099 (Box 1)
  - Banner, 33 x 68 inches. Red and white wool felt with Sigma Nu fraternity emblem, 1948; Accession ARCH-2017-001 (Box 1)
  - Banner, 13" x 29" red, white, tan velvet with fringe., ARCH-AM-1984-16 (Box 1)
  - Banner, "Stanford 1913", 5 x 3 cm. Red and white., ARCH-AM-1984-61 (Box 1)
  - Banner, red background with white Block S/Tree, "I AM Season Ticket Member" logo at bottom in white, 2017; ARCH-AM-2018-001 (Box 1)
  - Banner, red felt with "STANFORD" in white letters. Very Large, ARCH-AM-2003-009 (Box 1)
  - Banner; Stanford color, no printing, swallow tail on thin pole. 33x20 cm; crooked pole 84 cm., ARCH-AM-00-269 (Box 1)
  - Banner: "Gay People's Union at Stanford," 45"x79" red, white, black, and purple., ARCH-AM-1984-08 (Box 1)
  - Banner: canvas, painted. 4' x 8' red, white, black. "Gay People's Union at Stanford.", ARCH-AM-1983-02 (Box 1)
  - Barette - Stanford University seal, sterling silver, ARCH-AM.2014-020; 1 item(s) (Box 1)
  - Baseball cap, Rose Bowl, 2014; ARCH-AM.2014-014.2 (Box 1)
    Front - "Stanford Rose Bowl Game 2014 Pasadena, CA, 100th" Side - "2014 100th Rose Bowl Game presented Vizio"
  - Baseball caps, undated; ARCH-AM-2011-001 (Box 1)
    4 caps, red wool with white letter S 1 cap, black cap, red bill, with white letter S
  - Baseball uniform: short pants, short-sleeved shirt, cap (matches PH's of 1913-1914 uniforms), ARCH-AM-1991-096 (Box 1)
  - Basket, oval, 33 X 13 cm. Inlaid design on outside, red inside., ARCH-AM-00-146 (Box 1)
  - Basketball t-shirts: NCAA Final 4 1998 and Pac-10 Champions 1999, ARCH-AM-2004-011 (Box 1)
    2004-011.1 NCAA Final 4 1998 2004-011.2 1999 Pac-10 Champions
  - Beanie, Gray, ARCH-AM-00-170 (Box 1)
  - Beanie, Red. Felt., ARCH-AM-2015-007 (Box 1)
  - Banner, Red Felt with Fringe (Indian mascot era), before 1972; Accession ARCH-2018-006 (Box 1)
    Red felt with white "Block S" on one side, and "Stanford on other," fringe around all sides.
  - Beanies, red felt (2) and Stanford Indian decal, circa 1929; ARCH-AM-2017-021 (Box 1)
    AM-2017-021.01 Red felt beanie (plain); AM-2017-021.02 red felt beanie "1929 Stanford-21 Cal-6; Stanford-0 USC-7" written on brim in pen; AM-2017-021.03 Stanford Indian decal
  - Beat Cal and Sunken Diamond buttons, circa 1985-2001; ARCH-AM-2009-007 (Box 1)
    2009-007.1 Beat Cal button ca. 1985 (white letters on red) 2009-007.2 Sunken Diamond 2001 (S with tree superimposed over baseball)
  - Belt buckle "Stanford" in block letters, in metal, ARCH-AM-1977-06 (Box 1)
  - Belt buckle with red "S" from Chan's student day, 1930s; ARCH-AM-1995-32 (Box 1)
  - Bible. New Testament. 1898. 13X9X2 cm inscribed by Mrs. Stanford. Placed in cornerstone., ARCH-AM-00-128 (Box 1)
  - Big Game buttons, 1977 (one); 1978 (two); 1979 (one), 1977-1979; ARCH-AM-1980-11 (Box 1)
  - Big Game Commemorative wine bottles (empty); "This wine was specially selected by the Stanford Alumni Association. Proceeds from the wine sale help support alumni activities worldwide.", ARCH-AM-1997-022 (Box 1)
    97-22.1 1993 Willamette Valley Chardonnay, label by Jose Ortega "Full Moon on the Quad" 97-22.2 1994 Dry Creek Valley Chardonnay, label from 1927 yearbook (illus. of Big Game action)
  - Big Game mug, 1979; ARCH-AM-1979-15 (Box 1)
  - Big Game Mug, 1979 Nov 17; ARCH-AM.2014-021 (Box 1)
    Mug (stein) with Axe and Stanford and Cal helmets. "The Big Game" on top in red and "Stanford Stadium November 17, 1979" in blue at bottom. 1892-1978 Big Game scores on reverse.
  - Big Game Ribbon. 18x6.5 cm. White on red., 1975; ARCH-AM-00-200.1 (Box 1)
  - Black dress and coat believed to belong to Jane Stanford, ARCH-AM-1992-11 (Box 1)
  - Black metal dispatch box, 33X23X16 cm. "F.B.L." initials & key attached. [probably Francis B. Loomis], ARCH-AM-00-150 (Box 1)
  - Blank field book for the Stanford Geological Survey, 1932; ARCH-AM-2000-044 (Box 1)
  - Blank Stanford University class roll books, ARCH-AM-2002-34 (Box 1)
    2002-34.1 class roll book for 2 hour class 2002-34.2 class roll book for 5 hour class 2002-34.3 class roll book for 5 hour class
  - Blanket with block S presented to William Laughlin McLaine (designer of the Block S) by Stanford, ARCH-AM-2006-022 (Box 1)
  - Blanket, red wool with "LSJr.U" embroidery, circa 1891; Accession ARCH-2018-007 (Box 1)
    Purchased at auction in 1943 to benefit the Stanford Home for Convalescent Children. Purported to be made at the request of Jane Lathrop Stanford from the wool of a sheep shorn on 'the Farm.'
  - Blanket, supposedly given to women students in 1890s., ARCH-AM-1995-15 (Box 1)
  - Block "S" sweater: red, wool turtleneck, ARCH-AM-1995-25 (Box 1)
  - Block "S", women's sports 1915, ARCH-AM-1978-14 (Box 1)
  - Blowup of "check" to President Gerhard Casper of $3,000 for the President's Scholars Program, Oct. 20, 1999; ARCH-AM-2000-020 (Box 1)
  - Blue t-shirt "Out on the Farm," 1983 Gay and Lesbian Awareness week., ARCH-AM-1984-10 (Box 1)
  - Blue t-shirt with white lettering "Tenure Estelle Freedman, Sisters, bloody feet have worn smooth the path by which you came," 1982., ARCH-AM-1983-11 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees photograph, 1924; ARCH-AM-2011-005 (Box 1)
  - Bola tie, with Stanford Lil Injun clasp; white cord. (clasp design painted, red & white on black)., ARCH-AM-1980-04 (Box 1)
  - Bookplate: Metal sheet, 13x10 cm x 1 mm. Hopkins Transportation Library., ARCH-AM-00-233 (Box 1)
  - Bottle of Bookmaker's Ale 1997. Brewed and bottled by Anchor Brewing Co. for the Celebration of Books and Book People (at Stanford) June 27, 1997, ARCH-AM-2009-028 (Box 1)
  - Bottle of wine: Page Mill Winery 1994 Santa Clara County Chardonnay. Gibbons Reserve. back label on bottle: Endowed faculty chairs acquired by the Stanford School of Engineering during the Deanship of James F. Gibbons [followed by list and signature of holders], ARCH-AM-2007-007 (Box 1)
  - Bottles of wine (2): Angelica by Palo Alto Vineyard, 1889 (full) [1 bottle removed and given to outgoing Bd of Trustees, Burt McMurtry, June 2008], ARCH-AM-2005-038 (Box 1)
  - Bound, mounted souvenir menu (signed by guests) from New York Alumni Reunion dinner 1902. Red leather, on cover: "To Mrs. Leland Stanford from her boys in grateful appreciation of her hospitality January 28, 1902 New York City", ARCH-AM-1999-010 (Box 1)
  - Bow and card attached to tube that held poster from event (this one addressed to Mike Keller) - [for signed poster see Po 201-18 copy 6], ARCH-AM-1999-006 (Box 1)
  - Box used for box lunches during 2000 Stanford presidential inauguration events; red cardboard with top half of the seal and the words "Inauguration 2000" in white, ARCH-AM-2003-012 (Box 1)
  - Brandy glass, class of '46, 14 x 6 cm., ARCH-AM-1984-41 (Box 1)
  - brass bell from Sequoia Hall (?), given to Crane by Bill Gunther who worked in Sequoia, ARCH-AM-1998-006 (Box 1)
  - Brass cast of the Stanford University seal with motto., ARCH-AM-2017-025 (Box 1)
  - Brass plaque "built especially for LS Jr University by Rix & Birrell, San Francisco, 1891" Cast by Diamond Machine Co., ARCH-AM-1978-12 (Box 1)
  - Brass plaque of the S. U. Seal with the motto in German. 8.5" wide, plus spode plates with S.U. scences., ARCH-AM-1988-111 (Box 1)
  - Brass plaque with Stanford seal (Die Luft...), ARCH-AM-1979-14 (Box 1)
  - bronze bas-relief of David Star Jordan in profile (11.5 x 17 inches), made to be mounted to a wall, ARCH-AM-1999-011 (Box 1)
  - Bronze bas-relief of David Starr Jordan in profile (11.5 x 17 inches), ARCH-AM-2014-005 (Box 1)
  - Bronze Plaque, of William T. Ross who tutored Leland Jr. By Lora W. Steere 1920., ARCH-AM-00-245 (Box 1)
  - Bud vase, wheelock, Dresden Blue Vase, with painting of MemChu from Arch. 6.5x12mm., circa 1905; ARCH-AM-1980-07 (Box 1)
  - Bumper Sticker. 5.5x7.3 cm. Stanford Football, KSFO 560, Red on white., ARCH-AM-00-201 (Box 1)
  - Bust of Ewald Flugel., ARCH-AM-2002-30 (Box 1)
  - Bust of Jane Lathrop Stanford, ARCH-AM-00-008 (Box 1)
  - Bust, J.C. Branner; white. Made by E. Norton, 1921, 45x85 cm., ARCH-AM-00-257 (Box 1)
  - Bust, plaster, of John Casper Branner (painted brown), ARCH-AM-1985-03 (Box 1)
  - Bust, plaster, of David Starr Jordan (painted brown), ARCH-AM-1985-02 (Box 1)
  - Bust; framed, metal profile of George Mann Richardson. frame 92x72, image 67x42 cm., ARCH-AM-00-317 (Box 1)
  - Bust: David Starr Jordan. 56 cm hi x 128 cm diam. at base. Bronze-like material., ARCH-AM-00-258 (Box 1)
  - Button (Pin) 5.8 cm Stanford Half Century Club. 1926-1976, ARCH-AM-00-197 (Box 1)
  - Button (Pin) 5.8 cm. Cal St. Cable Car. White backround, 100th., ARCH-AM-00-198 (Box 1)
  - Button for the Rose Bowl: "Stanford Cardinal Tournament of Roses January 1st 2000" with images of football helmet and the official rose of the rose bowl., ARCH-AM-2000-001 (Box 1)